monitor.us 2018-06-14

# Privacy and Cookies Policy – Monitis

Monitis, a TeamViewer company, Global Privacy Policy   
Last modified: May, 2018 

### Introduction

The Monitis ("we / us") respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy. 

This policy (together with our Terms of Service and any other documents referred to in it) describes the personal information that we collect from you, or that you provide on this website [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) (our "Website") and how that information may be used or disclosed by us. 

This policy does not apply to information collected on any third-party site or by any third-party application that may link to or be accessible from the Website. 

Please read the following carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as your name, address, email addresses, user behavior. By using or accessing our Website, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time and your continued use of the Website is deemed to be acceptance of such changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

We, the Monitis US LLC, take protection of your personal data very seriously. The following policy provides an overview of how we ensure this protection and what kind of data is processed for what purpose. 

### A. Controller respectively Provider 

Monitis US LLC (“Monitis”), 5741 Rio Vista Drive, Largo, FL, USA, [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com), provides this website. In accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) Monitis is controller of your personal data. 

### B. Data Protection Officer

Monitis US LLC appointed Mr. Iskikian as data protection officer, who can be reached at [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com) to the attention of Mr. Barkev Iskikian, 5741 Rio Vista Drive, Largo, FL, USA. 

### C. Categories of Data 

Monitis collects and processes different categories of personal data depending on the respective service used by you. The following paragraph outlines the categories of data processed by category of service. 

#### I. Use of Monitis website – www.monitis.com

**1\. Protocol Data** : When you visit the Monitis website for informational purposes, i.e. you are not logged into a Monitis account and/or register for any service or feature, we collect the following personal data transmitted by your server: 

  * IP address
  * Date and time of the request
  * Time zone difference from Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  * Content of the request (specific site)
  * Access status / HTTP status code
  * Volume of data transmitted each time
  * Website from which the request comes
  * Browser
  * Operating system and its interface
  * Language and version of the browser software
  * The country of origin for the visitor

Where, according to local law, IP addresses and the like are considered personal information, then we treat it as such. The information we collect is merely statistical data about our users' equipment, browsing actions and patterns and does not and cannot identify any individual. 

**2\. Cookies:**  
Cookies are small files stored on the browser or the hard drive of your computer. Use of cookies help us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to: estimate our audience size and usage patterns, store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests, speed up your searches and recognize you when you return to our Website. 

A list of cookies we use, and their purpose, can be found below:

Name | Source | Purpose  
---|---|---  
__qca |  Various | This cookie is used to measure the websites 'audience reach' using data including IP address, referring HTTP location, search string, time of access, and other statistics.  
__utmc| Various | This takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves a site.  
SAPISID| [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is used a part of the Google + sharing facility.  
bcookie | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
__utma | Various | This cookie keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site pertaining to the cookie, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred. Google Analytics uses the information from this cookie to calculate things like Days and Visits.  
__utmz | Various | Keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine you used, what link you clicked on, what keyword you used, and where they were in the world when you accessed the website.  
__utmv | Various | This is a Google Analytics cookie. It is used for user-custom variables  
__utmb | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a Google Analytics cookie. It takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters a site.  
_leo_profile | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
_lipt | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
lang | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
rememberme | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
SS | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
HSID | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
SSID | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
APISID | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie  
PREF | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie.  
NID | [google.com](https://plus.google.com/117905979449296396502/posts) | This is a Google Analytics cookie.  
SID | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
visit | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
leo_auth_toekn | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
JSESSIONID | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
Persistence Cookie | [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Monitis-IT-Monitoring-Management-Services-1952939?itemaction=mclk&anetid=1952939&impid=&pgkey=anet_search_results&actpref=anetsrch_name&trk=anetsrch_name&goback=.gdr_1340716428293_1_*2) | This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
X-LI-IDC | [twitter.com](http://twitter.com/monitis) | This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
guest_id | [twitter.com](http://twitter.com/monitis) | This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
pid | [twitter.com](http://twitter.com/monitis) | This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
twll | [twitter.com](http://twitter.com/monitis) | This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
k | [twitter.com](http://twitter.com/monitis) | This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website.  
expandcollapse | [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) | Keep user preference to expand or collapse modules  
userId | [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) | Unique user id to keep user login state  
activeTabId  | [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) | Last active tab id, to select that tab after login  
recentlyVisitedTabs  | [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) | tab names recently visited to use for tab search  
adv | Various | ADV number to track Marketing campaigns  
loc | Various | LOC number to track Marketing campaigns  
Referrer | Various | To track referrers   
cookie_consent | [www.monitis.com ](http://www.monitis.com/) | This is a cookie used by Monitis to record visitors consent for collecting the cookies.  
  
If you register with us or if you continue to use our website, you agree to our use of cookies. You can refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website. 

Web Beacons, also known as pixel tags are electronic images, contained on a website that permit us to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). Web beacons are not used to access your personal information on the Website and are only used to compile aggregated statistics concerning use of the Website.

We use a trusted third party to provide you with the ability to opt - out from collecting cookies, if you do not wish to have cookies, please click here: [http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/2o7#optout.](http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/2o7#optout)

In addition, you may also set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.

This website uses social buttons to enable sharing of pages and third-party services to display media. As such, cookies and scripts from third party sites have been used and these third parties may be gathering usage information.

**3\. Web analytics, social media plugins, remarketing tools and third party integrated services:** Monitis uses web analytic applications (please refer to G. for further information), remarketing tools for advertisement purposes (please refer to H. for further information), security features used for our product (please refer to I. for further information), social media plugins (please refer to J. for further information) and third party integrated services (please refer to K. for further information). By and through these applications and tools, the aforementioned personal data of our users are collected. For further information on those tools and applications, please proceed to relevant provision below and review the description provided there. 

#### II. Submit a Ticket

If you submit a ticket for your Monitis product from Monitis dashboard, Zendesk 1019 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103 will process your email address. 

If you contact Sales/Support Team via LiveChat, Suite 1400, Boston, MA 02110-2619, USA from the Monitis website during non-working hours, and no Sales/Support Team member is online, the request will be submitted to Zendesk 1019 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA as a ticket, and Zendesk will process your name, email, name, type of question and optional information as company.

If you contact Sales/Support Team via LiveChat, Suite 1400, Boston, MA 02110-2619, USA from the Monitis website during working hours, LiveChat will process your personal data as your name, email, name, type of question and optional information as company, provided when initiating the live chat. This means that Zendesk 1019 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA and LiveChat, Suite 1400, Boston, MA 02110-2619, USA receive your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

#### III. Use of Monitis’ User Voice

**Email and inquiry** : When you contact us through the User Voice within the product, your first name, last name, email, and inquiry will be processed by User Voice 20 Newburn St, Lambeth, London SE11 5PJ, UK. 

This means that User Voice 20 Newburn St, Lambeth, London SE11 5PJ, UK receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

Please contact [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use. 

#### IV. Use of Quote Request Feature

**First name, last name, email, phone, company, country and inquiry** : If you request a quote for one of our products, Monitis will collect your first name, last name, email, phone number, country, your company information, and inquiry; Wherever we collect your personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

#### V. Place Order Feature

**First name, Last name, Company, Country, Address, Phone, E-Mail Address, payment method (PayPal, Credit Card, Invoice, Debit Card)** : We will process your first name, last name, email, company, phone, country, and your chosen payment method if you purchase Monitis service. Wherever we collect your personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

#### VI. Download through Apple App Store

If you click on the “Download on the App Store”-button to download Monitis, you are being forwarded to the Apple App Store, a service provided by Apple Inc., 1 Infinite Loop, Cupertino, California, USA, 95014. This means that Apple Inc. receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR. 

#### VII. Download through Google Play

If you click on the “Android App On Google Play”-button to download Monitis to your Android phone, you are being forwarded to Google Play, a service provided by Google, Inc., Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. This means that Google, Inc. receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

####  VIII. Newsletter Subscription 

**Email-address** : If you sign up for our newsletter, Monitis will collect your email address by obtaining your consent. Please note that Monitis uses the so-called double opt-in method by which you receive a confirmation email after you provided us with your email address to subscribe to our newsletter. If you do not confirm your email address within 24 hours, Monitis will delete your newsletter request. You may revoke your consent for the processing of your email address for newsletter receipt at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@monitis.com](mailto:privacy@monitis.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use. 

**Name, Email-Address and Website** : If you want to post a comment in our blog, you can post it via any of available Social Network accounts (Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; Google+ **Google Inc.** , 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA;) or DISQUS (717 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA) will process your name and email address. This means that Facebook, Twitter, Google+ or DISQUS receive your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR. 

You may comment publicly on different subjects concerning Monitis’ activities and products in Monitis’ Blog. Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name. We recommend using an assumed name instead of your real name. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines; therefore, please check prior to posting if your comment contains personal data. 

#### IX. Blog

**E-Mail Address** : Monitis will process your email address if you subscribe to our blog. 

**Name, Email-Address and Website** : If you want to post a comment in our blog, you can post it via any of available Social Network accounts (Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; Google+ **Google Inc.** , 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA;) or DISQUS (717 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA) will process your name and email address. This means that Facebook, Twitter, Google+ or DISQUS receive your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

You may comment publicly on different subjects concerning Monitis’ activities and products in Monitis’ Blog. Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name. We recommend using an assumed name instead of your real name. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines; therefore, please check prior to posting if your comment contains personal data. 

#### X. Monitis Customer Satisfaction Surveys 

If you participate in the Monitis Customer Satisfaction Surveys, we will collect your **name** , **email address** and **user experience** in a survey provided by Survey Monkey (SurveyMonkey, One Curiosity Way, San Mateo, CA 94403, USA). 

This means that Survey Monkey receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

### D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing 

To the extent Monitis is required to process any of your personal data in order to comply with a legal obligation we are processing your personal data on basis of Art. 6 par. 1 c) General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”). 

**I. Website use** : We want to ensure that when you visit any part of Monitis’ website your journey will be user-friendly, particularly that you do not encounter technical problems and malfunctions. In order to manage our relationship with you or your business we collect the following data to serve our business purposes such as 

  * to understand the performance of our website that hold Monitis product, business or support information;
  * to present our Monitis website and its content in a suitable and effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to communicate with you about our products and services;
  * to develop and manage our products and services;
  * to carry out our obligations, process and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * to serve our business improvement needs; 
  * to develop and carry out marketing activities;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our services, when you choose to do so.

Legal basis for processing personal data outlined under C. 1. is a user agreement concerning the use of our website, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. 

**II. Contact our Sales Team** : If you place an inquiry with us by using the contact form, Monitis needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data is a service agreement, i.e. Art. 6 para 1 lit. b) GDPR. In case you submit additional data based on your consent, the legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

**III. Submit a Ticket** : If you submit a ticket, we will process your personal data to answer your inquiry. We use this feature to fulfil our business purpose of authentication of our product users and provide service resolution for our customers. Legal basis for such processing is a service agreement and our contractual obligation to perform on our contract to provide you with our service, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. A

**IV. Feedback feature** : If you place an inquiry with us by using the in-product support feature or through our website, Monitis needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request and to provide the requested support. Information collected in this way serves several business purposes including but not limited to 

  * to test new services and features;
  * to manage how we work with other companies that provide services to us and our customers;
  * to develop new ways to meet our customer needs and to grow our business.

Legal basis for processing your personal data is a service agreement concerning the requested support and/or performance of the already existing agreement with you, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. In case you submit additional data based on your consent, the legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

**V. Quote request** : If you request a quote for our product, Monitis needs your personal data in order for us to process your request. Information collected in this way helps us 

  * to develop products and services, and to convey what we charge for them;
  * to seek your consent when we need it to contact you; and 
  * to be efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties.

Legal basis for processing your personal data is your request prior to entering into a contract, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. 

**VI. Place Order feature** : If you purchase our product by said means, Monitis needs your personal data for the performance of a contract. This information is required for our business to serve the purpose of 

  * to receive and manage customer payments; and
  * to collect and recover money that is owed to us.

Legal basis is therefore Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. 

**VII. Apple App Store** : In order for Monitis to offer Monitis monitoring service for iPhone, we embedded a hyperlink to Apple Inc.’s App Store to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to the App Store is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. 

**VIII. Google Play** : In order for Monitis to offer Monitis monitoring service for Android products, we embedded a hyperlink to Google Inc.’s Play Store to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to Google Play is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. 

**IX. Newsletter Subscription** : If you sign up for our newsletter, Monitis needs your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. Newsletter help us to serve our business purposes such as 

  * to manage our relationship with you or your business; and 
  * to develop and carry out marketing activities.

Legal basis for providing you with the newsletter is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may revoke at any time with effect for the future. 

**X. Blog** : Monitis’ Blog helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform where issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. Monitis also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defense in the event that a third party complains about your Blog comment’s content. In such case, Monitis needs to be able to contact you. Legal basis for such processing is a user agreement concerning the use of our Blog and our legitimate interest of legal defense, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

### E. Recipients

Monitis has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. Monitis will transfer your personal data to mandatory third parties for providing the monitoring service and to optional third-party services if we offer participation in campaigns, contests, reservations, or contract agreements in conjunction with a third party. 

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction. Monitis employees, who administer, maintain and further develop Monitis’ product and services will receive access to your personal data. 

If you use our **product** , contact us through the **contact feature** , **support** and **feedback features** , if you request a **quote** , and/ or if you **subscribe to our newsletter** , Monitis employees that are responsible for the respective service will receive access to your personal data. 

If you post a comment in Monitis’ **Blog** , your comment content and name/user name will be publicly available and may appear in search engines. Aside from Monitis employees, employees of available Social Networks (Facebook, Twitter, Google+) and DISQUS will receive access to your personal data as described under **C. I.** if comment in Monitis’ Blog. 

Please note that Monitis uses SSL technology encryption for payments to prevent unauthorized third-party access to your financial data. If you download Monitis through the **Apple App Store** , employees of Apple Inc. receive access to your personal data as described under **C. VI.**. Similarly, if you download Monitis through **Google Play** , employees of Google Inc. receive access to your personal data as described under **C. VII.**. 

Except as mentioned under **G.** , **H.** , **I.** , and **J.** concerning data transfers to the USA and for group internal IT services provided from outside the EU, US and Armenia, Monitis will not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. Monitis will transfer your personal data only when required to so by law or orders from the relevant authority. 

The data Monitis collects from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for Monitis or for one of its suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. Monitis will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

### F. Retention Periods for Personal Data

Your personal data will be deleted once you revoked consent, or the purpose for processing has ceased to exist. In some cases, Monitis is legally obligated to retain data for a certain period. Once this period has lapsed, Monitis will delete the data in accordance with data protection obligations. 

**I. Cookies** : Please click [here](http://www.monitis.com/privacy-cookies-policy#cookies) to access our Cookies Policy for further information. 

**II. Contact information** : Monitis is legally obligated to retain support feature requests from customers concerning product support inquiries in accordance with § 257 HGB and § 147 AO for a minimum of six and a maximum period of 10 years. With regard to personal data provided through contact requests, Monitis will retain such request for three months following closure of the request and delete such data thereafter. 

**III. Submit a Ticket** : Personal data provided in connection with a ticket submitted will be retained for as long as the ticket is open. Once your inquiry has been answered, Monitis will retain such data for a three (3) month period.

**IV. Feedback feature** : Personal data provided in connection with feedback features are retained for three months following submission of feedback; Monitis will delete such data thereafter. 

**V. Quote request** : Personal data provided in connection with quote requests is retained by Monitis for three months following the period of quote validity, provided no ensuing contract was concluded. Provided the quote request lead to conclusion of a contract, please refer to **F. II.** for information on retention periods. 

**VI. Place Order Feature** : Personal data provided in connection with a product purchase, i.e. address- and payment information as well as the order date, is retained by Monitis for a minimum period of 6 years in accordance with § 257 HGB, and a maximum period of 10 years in accordance with § 147 AO. 

**VII. Apple App Store** : Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under **C. VII.** will be retained by Apple Inc. Please refer to <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/> for further information. 

**VIII. Google Play** : Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under **C. VIII.** will be retained by Google Inc. Please refer to [ https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US) for further information. 

**IX. Newsletter** : Personal data provided in connection with a subscription to our newsletter will be retained for as long as the subscription is valid. Upon revocation of your consent, your personal data will be deleted entirely. 

**X. Blog** : Personal data provided in connection with your Blog subscription will be retained until you deregister. 

### G. Web Analytics 

#### I. Google Analytics

Monitis uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Ireland Ltd. (" **Google** "), with its business address at Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. Google Analytics uses "Cookies", i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and enable analysis of your website use. Monitis uses Google Analytics with the extension "_anonymizeIp()". Thereby, IP addresses are processed in a shortened form and no direct reference to individuals is possible. Monitis uses Google Analytics to analyze and improve its website. Monitis receives statistics which help us to make our online presence more interesting for you. Legal basis to use Google Analytics is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The information generated by cookies about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. If you enable IP anonymization on this website, your IP address from Google will be shortened within Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google has subjected itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield for any such exceptional cases in which your personal data will be transmitted to the USA; further information is available under www.privacy-shield.gov/EU-US-Framework. Google will on behalf of Monitis use this information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activity, and provide other services regarding website and internet use to Monitis. 

In addition, Monitis’ website uses Google Analytics for cross-device analysis of user streams, which are enabled through User-IDs. If you have a customer account, you may disable such cross-device analysis by <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010>

The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of the Google Analytics will apparently not be merged with other data from Google.

As further explained in our [Cookies Policy](http://www.monitis.com/privacy-cookies-policy#cookies), you may block cookies from being stored on your device by adjusting the settings in your browser software; however, in such case, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionalities of our website and Monitis product. You can also block the collection of the data generated by the cookie and the data related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing a browser plugin available from the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Please visit the following homepage for an overview on data protection: [ http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html), as well as the privacy policy: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en.](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

#### II. Google Tag Manager

Additionally, Monitis uses Google Tag Manager, tracking and conversion tool provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA.

#### III. Google Display Feature

Our website uses third party cookies from Google Analytics for Display Advertisers, including the following features. No personal data is processed within those services:

  * **Remarketing with Google Analytics**

The integrations between both our web analytics and paid advertising platforms together to give us additional insight. This allows us to tailor our advertising to ensure the right types and offers are shown to you while you are using the internet outside our website.

  * **Google Display Network Impression Reporting**

Which gives us additional insight into who has viewed our paid digital advertising on other websites. This will help us optimize and tailor our advertising.

  * **Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting**

Which gives us insight into behaviour information relating to visitor age, gender and interests on an anonymous and aggregate level. This will help us to understand browsing behaviour to give you a better experience whilst visiting our sites.

#### IV. reCAPTCHA

Monitis uses reCAPTCHA to protects our website from spam and abuse. reCAPTCHA is a service provided by Google that uses an advanced risk analysis engine and adaptive CAPTCHAs to keep automated software from engaging in abusive activities on our site. It does this while letting valid users pass through with ease.

reCAPTCHA allows Monitis to verify if an interaction is legitimate without any user interaction. It is a purely JavaScript API returns a score giving the us the ability to take action in the context of our site: for instance, requiring additional factors of authentication, sending a post to moderation, or throttling bots that may be scraping content.

reCAPTCHA handles no personal information. Please visit the following page for an overview of reCAPTCHA [https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/.](https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/)

### H. Remarketing Applications 

#### I. Google AdWords Conversion

Monitis’ website uses Google AdWords, in order to generate attention for our services by using advertisement on third party websites. Based on data generated by such advertisement campaigns, we are able to determine the success rate of our advisement campaigns. Thereby, Monitis tries to provide you with advertisement that is of interest to you, to make its website more interesting, and calculates advertising expenses fairly. Legal basis for such processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Such means of advertisement are delivered by Google AdWords. Provided you clicked on an ad delivered by Google and which redirected you to our website, a cookie is stored on your computer by Google AdWords. These cookies usually expire within 30 days and are not supposed to be used to personally identify a user. In addition to these cookies, analytic values like unique cookie ID, quantity of Ad impressions per storing, last impression and opt-out information (markings that the user does not want to be addressed any further) are usually stored. These cookies enable Google to recognize your internet browser. If you visit certain pages on our website and provided the cookie stored on your computer has not yet expired, Monitis and Google are able to recognize that you clicked on an ad and were redirected to the Monitis website. Every Google AdWords customer gets a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked across sites by AdWords customers. Monitis does not process personal data by and through the aforementioned advertisement campaigns. Monitis merely receives statistical evaluations from Google. By and through these statistical evaluations, we can plainly see which advertisement campaign was particularly effective. Any additional data generated by use of the advertisement is not forwarded to Monitis; particularly, we cannot identify users through this information. Through the marketing tool, your browser automatically connects to Google’s server. Google has subjected itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield, further information can be obtained under [ www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework ](http://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework). Please note, that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are beyond Monitis’ control. We thus inform you based on our own knowledge: By integrating AdWords, Google receives information that you visited a particular Monitis website or part thereof, and/or that you clicked on one of our advertisements. If you are registered with one of Google’s services, Google is able to match your visit to your Google account. Google may receive your IP address and/or may store it even if you are not registered with one of Google’s services and/or if you have not been logged in. You may avoid tracking in various ways: 

a) Through a setting of your browser software, particularly, by suppressing third party cookie installation that will prevent that you receive third party ads;

b) Through deactivating AdWords Cookies, by setting your browser so that cookies from www.googleadservices.com are being blocked; this can be done under [www.google.com/settings/ads](http://www.google.com/settings/ads), however, such settings are deleted if you delete cookies;

c) Through permanently deactivating cookies in your Firefox, Internet Explorer or Google Chrome under www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin. Please note that if you deactivate these cookies, you may not be able to use all functionalities of our website. 

Further information on Google’s data privacy can be found under www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy. Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies for interest-based advertising via the advertising network initiative, by following the instructions at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

#### II. Google Remarketing

Monitis uses Google Remarketing in addition to AdWords. This is an application that allows us to address you again. After visiting our website and while you are surfing the internet, our advertisement can be displayed to you by and through this application. This is enabled by cookies stored in your browser which track and analyse user behavior on different websites for Google. Google can track your previous visit to our website. According to its own statement, Google does not combine data gathered through remarketing with any personal data Google may have stored about you. Furthermore, pseudonymization is being used as part of remarketing. If you do not want to use the remarketing feature from Google, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at [http://www.google.com/settings/ads.](http://www.google.com/settings/ads)

#### III. Social Media Plugins

Currently, we use social media plugins (“ **plugins** ”) from **Facebook** , **Google+** , **LinkedIn** and **Twitter** (“ **plugin provider** ”).

Monitis uses Facebook plugins on our website which are provided by Facebook Inc. Facebook’s plugins are identifiable by the Facebook logo and/or the "thumbs up” - symbol. Monitis also uses the "+1" button from Google Plus on our website, which is operated by Google Inc.; the plugin is identifiable by the "+1" symbol on a white and colored background. Furthermore, Monitis uses the ”in” button from LinkedIn, which can be identified by a blue button. Additionally, Monitis uses the short messaging service Twitter Inc, which can be identified by a button that contains a bird. 

By using plugins, Monitis provides an opportunity to interact with social media and other social media users on its website. Plugins are provided to increase Monitis’ internet presence and make it more interesting to you. Legal basis for use of the plugins is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. 

Every time you visit our website and any part thereof that contains a plugin, the plugin causes your browser to directly connect with the plugin provider’s server. With regard to Facebook and its own statement, IP addresses collected within Germany are apparently anonymized right after collection. 

By activating the plugin, your personal data as described under C. is transmitted to and stored by the plugin provider, likely on a server in the USA. As personal data is collected by and through cookies, we recommend that you delete all cookies through security settings of your browser. Please note that data collection and processing are beyond Monitis’ control and we have neither been informed of the entire scope of data collection, purpose of the processing, nor any data retention periods. We have also not been informed if and when data is being deleted. With regard to Google and according to its own statement, Google stores your browsing history when you activate a "+1" button for a period of up to two weeks for system maintenance and troubleshooting purposes. 

Plugin provider store data collected about you as user profiles and use such data for advertisement purposes, market research and/or need based design of their websites. Evaluation of such data (even of users not logged in) is particularly used for need-based advertisements and to notify other users of the same social network of your activities on our website. 

You have a right of objection concerning such user profiling, however, you have to address such objection to the respective plugin provider. In order to properly address your demand, we provide you with the relevant addresses: 

  * **Facebook Inc.** , 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>; Additional information on data collection: <http://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084>, for further information on Facebook’s privacy refer to: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other> applications as well as <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-infoeveryoneinfo>. 
  * **Google Inc.** , 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA; for further information on Google’ privacy refer to: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/?hl=de>. 
  * **LinkedIn Corporation** , 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on LinkedIn’s privacy refer to: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy>.
  * **Twitter, Inc.** , 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on Twitter’s privacy refer to: [https://twitter.com/privacy. ](https://twitter.com/privacy)

Your data is being transmitted to the plugin provider, regardless if you maintain a profile with the plugin provider and/or if you are currently logged in. If you are currently logged into your social media profile, data collected on your visit of our website is directly matched to your social media profile. If you activate the plugin, e.g. by liking or retweeting our website, such information is stored in your social media profile and will be publicly shared with your contacts. We recommend that you log off your social media profile every time you are done using it, particularly, before you activate any plug-in buttons so that you can avoid a matching of data with your social media profile. For Facebook, you may also use a browser add-on called "Facebook Blocker" which is available at the following link <http://webgraph.com/resources/facebookblocker/> and which may prevent data collection and disclosure of your data in the future. 

### J. Integrated Third Party Service Tools

#### YouTube Videos

Monitis may integrate videos in our website, which are stored on www.youtube.com. These videos can be played on our website. When you visit the Monitis website, YouTube receives information on what particular website you visit. Your personal data as described under C. is transmitted to YouTube. Such transmission takes place, regardless if you are logged into your YouTube account, or if you do not maintain such account. If you are logged into your YouTube account, your personal data will be matched with your YouTube profile. If you do not wish that your personal data is being matched with your profile, you should log out of your YouTube account prior to activating a YouTube video. 

Legal basis for integration of YouTube Videos into our Monitis website is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Monitis uses YouTube videos to make our website more interesting to you and to integrate a service with which users may receive useful information about our services. 

YouTube stores your data as a user profile and uses your personal data for advertisement, market research and/or need-based design of its website. Evaluation of such personal data is done, even of user who were not logged into YouTube, for need-based advertisement and to inform other YouTube users of your activities on our website. 

Please note, that it is beyond Monitis’ control how long and in what way YouTube will retain your data. For further information concerning purpose and scope of data collection and processing, please visit [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en). 

You have a right to object to such processing of your personal data, however, you will have to address such right to YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. 

### K. Statutory/Contractual requirement 

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to use all of the functionalities of our website; where we ask for consent and you choose not to provide it, we may not be able to provide you with the information or service requested.

### L. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling 

Monitis does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making. As described under **G.** , **H.** , **I.** and **K.** , Monitis uses your personal data for profiling, unless you changed your browser settings to prevent cookie placements. Evaluation of your personal data by Google Analytics is done after your IP address has been abbreviated so that you can no longer be identified. 

###  M. Your Rights 

I. You may contact us by email at [datarequest@monitis.com](mailto:datarequest@monitis.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data by logging into your account;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data; 
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.  
For deleting your personal data (hence your Monitis account) send an email with your request to [delete.my.personal.data@monitis.com](http://www.monitis.com/delete.my.personal.data@monitis.com); 
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  *   * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights - have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. 

#### II. Your California privacy rights

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [privacy@monitis.com.](mailto:privacy@monitis.com)

#### III. The Freedom of Information Act

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee as applicable and in accordance with the laws of the country from which you are accessing the Website, to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

### N. Changes to our privacy policy

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. It is your responsibility to check this page from time to time to check for any change. Your continued use of the Website or our services shall be deemed to be your consent to such changes. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page.

### O. Contact information

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at: [privacy@monitis.com.](mailto:privacy@monitis.com)
